# **ELVIS SEGBEAYA**

Data Analyst Spring, TX · 346.264.6837

Segbeayaelvis@gmail.com · https://www.linkedin.com/in/elvis-segbeaya-024093199·

## **SUMMARY**

As a Data Analyst with over 5 years of industry experience applying data analysis methods to real-world business problems, I am skilled in all aspects of the data analysis/science project life cycle. Examples include exploring existing data for insights, developing and maintaining reports that enable end-users to make appropriate business decisions and using statistical or machine learning techniques to assess customer performance.

### **EDUCATION AND SKILLS**

The University of Texas May 2021-2022

**Masters of Technology Commercialization** 

The University of Houston 2017-2019

**Bachelor of Science in Mathematics w/ Computer Science** 

The University of Houston 2017-Ongoing

**Bachelor of Science in Computer Science** 

Tarrant County College 2012-2015

**Associate of Mathematics** 

# **Skills**

- Languages: Python, R, SAS, SQL, Java, C++, C#, JavaScript, LinQ, T-SQL, ASP.NET MVC
- Libraries: NumPy, Pandas, Scikit-Learn, Dplyr, NLTK
- Reporting Tools: Tableau, Power BI, Excel, MS Suite
- **Statistical Methods**: Regression Models, Ensemble Methods, Supervised/Unsupervised algorithms, Neural Networks, Random Forest, KNN, etc....
- Data Science: Machine Learning, Data Mining, Predictive Analytics, NLP, Data Sets
- Predictive Analytics, Data Cleaning/Mining, Text Analytics
- Database: SQL, T-SQL, MySQL, Oracle, MongoDB
- **Spoken Languages**: English[proficient], French[intermediate], Ewe[proficient]

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

[BNY Mellon] Analytics Analyst

May 2020–Present

- Provides analysis in the development of statistical, financial and/or econometric models
  for analyzing asset performance, securities data, derivative pricing, risk exposure or other
  sophisticated concepts.
- Provides analytical support and prepares drafts of standard and ad hoc reports for assigned area.
- Supports assigned area with basic statistical and quantitative analyses.

- Perform or oversee data management activities in support of more senior quantitative colleagues.
- Runs models, looks for exceptions, takes corrective action. Builds knowledge of technology tools used to conduct analyses.
- Applies techniques such as querying and macro development to extract data for populating models.
- Builds knowledge of processes and products and which analyses, methodologies and approaches best support assessment of performance, risk, or valuation.
- Interprets findings and prepares initial drafts of standard reports.
- Primarily responsible for the accuracy and quality of own work. Work contributes to the achievement of team goals.

#### •

# [Grocers Supply] Data Analyst

September 2018–June 2019

- Orchestrated and executed a data migration of over 40k products and merchandises.
- Amplified the revenue of the company by 20% through in-depth analysis of marketing evaluation and research.
- Streamlined multi-tier projects by spear-heading a coordinated effort of various departments.
- Improved overall profits and stimulated customer interests through innovative product creation and designs.
- Oversaw operations of product movement, inventory control, and price management.
- Organized in-store layout structure and instituted new design patterns.
- Used SSRS, store metrics and past data to forecast products and prices.
- Utilized Tableau to create dashboards to showcase sales, kpi, regional metrics.
- Gave quarterly updates of prices, sales, inventory using Tableau.

# [WageWorks] Account Consultant

July 2016-May 2018

- Designed and developed multi-level solutions for end clients.
- Cultivated and nurtured long term B2B relationships with customers nationwide.
- Leveraged expertise to empower clients to make well informed business decisions.

# [Allied Marketing] Quality Assurance Assistance [prior position: Data Entry Clerk] January 2015- June 2016

- Managed risk assessments, recovering over 50% of lost inventory.
- Used SQL to develop databases to manage and categorize inventory.
- Design and presented educational material for various departments.
- Assisted with the maintenance of e-mail and other internet applications.
- Handled B2B relations and resolved customer problems.

# [Monitronics] $3^{rd}$ Tier Technical Support

October 2012- December 2014

- Initiated and provided technical resolution for various alarm systems and products.
- Positively influenced consumer behavior when presenting various innovative products.
- Secured 85% retention rate with irate and confused clients.
- Yielded a 95% customer satisfaction rating.